[
    [
        {
            "question":"In an election between two candidates, 64% of the voters cast their votes, out of which 4% of the votes were declared invalid. A candidate got 12,288 votes which were 64% of the total valid votes. Find the total number of votes enrolled in that election.",
            "options":[30250,32152,31250,20152],
            "answer":31250,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"Ayush spends 25% of an amount of money on an insurance policy, 26% on food, 23% on children’s education and 19% on recreation. He deposits the remaining amount of ₹26,600 in the bank. What is the total amount (in ₹) that he spends on food and recreation together?",
            "options":[195000,183000,162000,171000],
            "answer":171000,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"The monthly income of an employee was ₹26,500 and his monthly expenditure was ₹22,000. Next year his income increased by 20% and his expenditure increased by 15%. Find the percentage increase in his savings.",
            "options":["44 4/9","44 7/9","44 5/9","44 8/9"],
            "answer":"44 4/9",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"The cost price of pulses is 12% less than the selling price. Using a faulty weighing machine, shopkeeper is able to earn 25% profit. How much percent of the faulty machine shows more weight as compared to the actual weight (Rounded off to the nearest integer)?",
            "options":[10,14,13,15],
            "answer":10,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"Swastik saves 20% of his income while spends the remaining amount on food, rent, education and shopping. 15% of the income is spent on food, while ₹12,800 is spent on rent, ₹32,000 on education and ₹7,200 on shopping. The amount spent on shopping is 11.25% of the total expenditure. How much money (in ₹) is spent on food?",
            "options":[9600,12000,15000,10800],
            "answer":12000,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"A number is first increased by 16% and then increased by 20%. The number so obtained is now decreased by 40%. The net decrease percentage in the original number is:",
            "options":["16 12/5","15 9/25","11 13/25","13 7/25"],
            "answer":"16 12/5",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"Two candidates A and B contested in an election. 80% of the voters cast their votes, out of which 2% of the votes were invalid. A got 9,408 votes which was 60% of the valid votes. Find the total number of votes.",
            "options":[12000,22000,20000,21000],
            "answer":20000,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"A number first increased by 8% and then decreased by 3% to get 2619. What is 5% of that number ?",
            "options":[125,135,130,140],
            "answer":125,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"A spends 68% of his monthly income. If A's monthly income increases by 25% and his monthly saving increases by 15%, then the percentage increase in his monthly expenditure will be:",
            "options":["27 13/17","29 12/17","33 7/17","31 6/17"],
            "answer":"29 12/17",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"Harsha's expenditure is 45% of her income. If the income from the next month is increased by 15% and the amount she saved each month remains the same, then find the percentage increase in her expenditure (rounded off to 2 decimal places).",
            "options":[33.33,15,45,27.50],
            "answer":33.33,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"The price of an article is increased by r%. The new price was decreased by r% later. Now the latest price is Rs.1.What was the original price of the article?",
            "options":["10000 / ( 10000 - r^2)","( 10000 - r^2 ) / 10000","100 / ( 100 - r^2 )","100 / ( 1 - r^2 )"],
            "answer":"10000 / ( 10000 - r^2)",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"Aditya buys 300 mangoes for Rs.1,100. Some of these mangoes are rotten and are thrown away. He sells the remaining mangoes at Rs.5 each and makes a profit of Rs.150. Find the percentage of mangoes thrown away",
            "options":["16 1/2","15 2/3","16 2/3","16 1/3"],
            "answer":"16 2/3",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"In an election, 15% of the voters on the voters list did not cast their votes and 100 voters cast their ballot paper blank. There were only two candidates Ram and Shyam. The winner, Ram, was supported by 69% of all the voters in the list and he got 630 votes more than Shyam. Find the number of voters on the list.",
            "options":[1200,1000,1100,1300],
            "answer":1000,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"If the price of rice is increased by 25 percent, then by what percentage consumption of rice should be decreased so that the expenditure incurred on rice gets decreased by 40 percent?",
            "options":[52,43.33,42,48],
            "answer":52,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"Shiva’s monthly salary is Rs.75,000. He spends Rs.12,000 on household items, Rs.14,000 on LIC and mutual funds, Rs.15,000 on his children’s education, and keeps Rs.10,000 for miscellaneous expenses. His savings are Rs.21,000 per month and he donates the rest of the amount to an orphanage. The percentage of his income that he donates is:",
            "options":[3,6,8,4],
            "answer":4,
            "category":"Percentage"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"The expenditure on the cost of living of a man and his family is 60% of his salary. He gets two increments of 30% and 60% in his salary. If his saving increases by 250% of his initial saving, then the new cost of living expenditure is what percentage (rounded off to the nearest integer) of the increased salary?",
            "options":[32.7,43.6,29.5,36.6],
            "answer":32.7,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"A mask manufacturing company manufactured ‘X’ number of masks in 2018. It increased its manufacturing capacity by 30% in 2019 and further increased its manufacturing by 15% in 2020. In 2021, due to the machinery breakdown, its manufacturing declined by 40%. What is the value of ‘X’ if it manufactured 179400 masks in 2021?",
            "options":[180000,230000,200000,210000],
            "answer":200000,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"The population of country A decreased by p% and the population of country B decreased by q% from the year 2020 to 2021. Here 'p' is greater than 'q'. Let 'x' be the ratio of the population of country A to the population of country B in the given year. What is the percentage decrease in 'x' from 2020 to 2021?",
            "options":["100(p-q)/(100-q)","100(p-q)/(100+q)","100(p-q)/(100-p)","100(p-q)/100"],
            "answer":"100(p-q)/(100-q)",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"In an election between two candidates, the defeated candidate secured 42% of the valid votes polled and lost the election by 7,68,400 votes. If 82,560 votes were declared invalid and 20% people did NOT cast their vote, then the invalid votes were what percentage (rounded off to 1 decimal place) of the votes which people did NOT cast ?",
            "options":[10.6,9.8,12.9,6.8],
            "answer":6.8,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"Sonam is a cab driver, who plies within a city. The number of kilometres that she drives on a Tuesday was 12.5% less than the number of kilometres that she drives on the day before.On the other hand, the number of kilometres that she drives on Wednesday was 20% more than the number of kilometres that she drives on Tuesday. If Sonam drives a total of 336 km on Wednesday, how many kilometers did she drive on Monday ?",
            "options":[315,318,320,324],
            "answer":320,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"In an election, there were three candidates: A, B and C. 10% of the eligible voters did not vote. Out of those who voted, 45% voted for A, 35% voted for B and the remaining 20% voted for C. 30% of the votes polled for A and 20% of the votes polled for B were later deemed invalid, while all the votes polled for C were deemed valid. If A got 882 more valid votes than B did, how many valid votes did C receive ",
            "options":[5020,5040,5050,5060],
            "answer":5040,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"A fruit seller sells 45% of the oranges that he has along with one more oranges to a customer . He then sells 20% of the remaining oranges and 2 more oranges to a second customer. He then sells 90% of the now remaining oranges to a third customer and is still left with 5 oranges. How many oranges did the fruit seller have initially?",
            "options":[100,111,121,120],
            "answer":120,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"By mistake, the reciprocal of a positive fraction got typed in place of itself, and thereby its value got reduced by 175/4%. What was the value of the fraction?",
            "options":["1/2","4/3","3/4","1/4"],
            "answer":"4/3",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"The income of A is 20% less than the income of B and the income of C is 70% of the sum of incomes of A and B. The income of D is 25% more than the income of C. If the difference between the incomes of B and D is Rs 23000, then what is the income (in Rs) of A?",
            "options":[32000,25000,26000,28000],
            "answer":32000,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"A certain number of students from school X appeared in an examination and 20% students failed. From school Y, 130% more students than that from school X, appeared in the same examination. If 90% of the total number of students appeared from both the schools passed, then what is the percentage of students from school Y who failed (correct to one decimal place) ",
            "options":[8.3,10,6.4,5.7],
            "answer":5.7,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"In a workshop with 80 students and 10 resource persons, sweets were distributed at the end of the workshop. The amount spent for distributing sweets to each student was 30% of the total number of students and the amount spent towards each resource person was 40% of the total number of students. The total amount spent for sweets distribution in the workshop was",
            "options":[2400,2440,2420,2240],
            "answer":2240,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"In a constituency, 55% of the total number of voters are males and the rest are females. If 40% of the males are illiterate and 40% of the females are literate, then by what percentage is the number of illiterate females more than that if the illiterate males(correct to the one decimal place)",
            "options":[22.7,16.4,21.5,20.8],
            "answer":22.7,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"A reduction of 20% in the price of sugar enables a purchaser to obtain 4 kg more for Rs.160. The original price of sugar per kg is:",
            "options":[12,10,14,15],
            "answer":10,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"A student multiplied a number with 3/4 instead of 4/3. What is the error percentage? ",
            "options":[59.67,43.75,67.45,39.34],
            "answer":43.75,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"A crate of fruits contains one spoiled fruit for every 25 fruits. 60% of the spoiled fruits were sold. If the seller had sold 48 spoiled fruits, then the number of fruits in the crate were:",
            "options":[2000,2400,3000,1200],
            "answer":2000,
            "category":"Percentage"
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question":"If each edge of a cube is increased by 10%, then the percentage increase in its surface area is:",
            "options":[21,19,22,20],
            "answer":21,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"In a school, 4% of the students did not appear for the annual exams. 10% of the students who appeared for the exams could not pass the exam. Out of the remaining students, 50% got distinction marks and 432 students passed the exam but could not get distinction marks. The total number of students in the school is:",
            "options":[960,1000,878,1200],
            "answer":1000,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"A, B and C donate 8%,7% and 9%, of their salaries respectively to a charitable trust. The salaries of A and B are the same and the difference between their donations is ₹259. The total donation of A and B is ₹1,185 more than that of C. The total donation of A and C is what percentage of the total salaries of A, B and C? (Correct to one decimal place)",
            "options":[6.2,5.8,6.4,7.1],
            "answer":5.8,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"The income of A is 60% less than that of B, and the expenditure of A is equal to 60% of B’s expenditure. If A’s income is equal to 70% of B’s expenditure, then what is the ratio of the savings of A and B?",
            "options":["3:8","5:9","4:7","2:15"],
            "answer":"2:15",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"The population of town B is 300% more than that of town A. For the next two years, the population of A increases by x% per year and that of B decreases by the same percentage per year. After 2 years, if the population of A and B become equal, then the value of x is ",
            "options":["30 2/3","40","25","33 1/3"],
            "answer":"33 1/3",
            "category":
        },
        {
            "question":"The monthly salary of a person was Rs.50,000. He used to spend on three heads- personal and family expenses (E), taxes(T), philanthropy (P), and the rest were his savings. E was 50% of the income, T was 20%of E and P was 15% of T. When his salary got raised by 40%, he maintained the average level of E, but T became 30% of E and P became 20% of T. By what percentage is the new savings more or less than the earlier savings?(correct upto one decimal place)",
            "options":["16.4 more","8.2 more","16.4 less","8.2 less"],
            "answer":"16.4 more",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"In an examination, A obtained 10% more marks than B, B obtained 20% more marks than C and C obtained 32% less marks that D. If A obtained 272 more marks than C, then the marks obtained by B is :",
            "options":[850,816,1020,952],
            "answer":1020,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"If A is 28% more than B and C is 25% less than the sum of A and B, then by what percent will C be more than A (correct to one decimal place)?",
            "options":[32.2,28,43,33.6],
            "answer":33.6,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"When the price of an item was reduced by 25%, then its sale was increased by x%. If there is an increase of 20% in the receipt of the revenue, then the value of x will be :",
            "options":[50,60,45,75],
            "answer":60,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"With reference to a number greater than one, the difference between itself and its reciprocal is 25% of the sum of itself and its reciprocal. By how much percentage (correct one decimal place) is the fourth power of the number greater than its square?",
            "options":[57.8,62.5,64.5,66.7],
            "answer":66.7,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"For an examination of a practical based subject, the total marks is 100. The break-up for theory, practical, project and viva voce is 40%, 30%, 20%, 10%. A candidate scored 80% in theory, 70% in practical, 60% in project and 50% in viva voce. What was her aggregate percentage ?",
            "options":[70,72,68,67],
            "answer":70,
            "category":
        },
        {
            "question":"Two students, A and B, appeared for an examination. A secured 8 marks more than B and the marks of the former was 55% of the sum of their marks. The marks obtained by A and B, respectively, are :",
            "options":["44 36","36 28","38 30","40 32"],
            "answer":"44 36",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"Sudha decided to donate 12% of her monthly income to an orphanage. On the day of donation, she changed her decision and donated a sum of Rs. 4800 which was equal to 80% of what she had decided earlier. What is 27% of her monthly income ?",
            "options":[13959,11934,14040,13500],
            "answer":13500,
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"If decreasing 120 by x% gives the same result as increasing 40 by x% then x% of 210 is what percent less than (x + 20)% of 180?",
            "options":["33 1/3","18","16 2/3","20"],
            "answer":"16 2/3",
            "category":"Percentage"
        },
        {
            "question":"The price of an article increases by 20% every year. If the difference between the prices at the end of the third and fourth years is Rs. 259.20, then 40% of the price (In Rs.) at the end of the second year is :",
            "options":[484,432,384,472],
            "answer":432,
            "category":"Percentage"
        }
    ]

]